原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     可爱Alien小闲汀  屯栗子  余欢
翻译     余欢  暴走小罐头  布塔
校对     超长MV打歌布塔
时间轴   西·查  caroline  紫夏  没有影子
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔
真恶心
Yuck.
火堆还有余温
The fire's still warm.
是你吗  隐士鲍勃
Is that you, Hermit Bob?
我们可以看见你
We kinda can see you.
农夫米勒说可能是你
Farmer Miller says you might have stole
偷走了他的一只鸡
one of his chickens.
这是违法的
That happens to be against the law.
我希望是只狐狸干的
Now, I'm hoping that it was a fox that did that.
操你丫的  克里夫
Up your hole with a wooden pole, Cliff.
这样做也是违法的
That also happens to be against the law.
要逮捕他吗
Should we take him in?
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
不知道
I don't know.
他不见了
I don't see him.
我们要回镇子里了
We're gonna go back to town now...
隐士鲍勃
Hermit Bob.
不要再违法了
Don't break any more laws.
冷静下来
Just calm down.
克里夫
Hey, Cliff.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
♪ 丧尸正如你我 ♪
♪ Oh, the dead don't die ♪
The Dead Don't Die - Sturgill Simpson
♪ 每日半死不活 ♪
♪ Any more than you or I ♪
♪ 他们只是活在 ♪
♪ They're just ghosts inside a dream ♪
♪ 虚妄的白日梦中 ♪
♪ Of a life that we don't own ♪
♪ 他们就在你我身边 ♪
♪ They walk around us all the time ♪
♪ 永远心不在焉 ♪
♪ Never paying any mind ♪
♪ 不管我们活得荒唐 ♪
♪ To the silly lives we lead ♪
♪ 还是死得凄凉 ♪
♪ Or the reaping we've all sown ♪
♪ 每个转角都有一杯咖啡 ♪
♪ There's a cup of coffee waiting on every corner ♪
♪ 有一天我们醒来 ♪
♪ Someday we're gonna wake up ♪
♪ 会发现转角不见了 ♪
♪ And find the corners gone ♪
♪ 但是丧尸仍独自 ♪
♪ But the dead will still be walking round ♪
♪ 在这旧世间漫步 ♪
♪ In this old world alone ♪
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on ♪
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on. ♪
丧尸未逝
我们是不是早晚要逮捕他
Should we bring him in one of these days?
我是说
I mean...
他可是朝警察开了枪
he fired a weapon at police officers.
不至于吧
Yeah, I don't know.
我觉得鸡根本不是他偷的
I doubt he even stole that chicken.
农夫米勒坏得要命
Farmer Miller is such an asshole.
我和鲍勃高中时就认识了
I've known Bob since junior high.
那都是五十年前的事了吧
That must have been like 50 years ago.
是啊
Yeah, it was.
鲍勃在林子里住了好多年了
You know, Bob's been out there for years,
以松鼠和虫子为食
eating squirrels and bugs,
据我所知  他从没伤害过谁
and he never hurt anyone that I ever heard of.
不过他有点不正常
Well, he is kind of unusual.
现在已经八点二十了吗
Is it already 20 after 8:00?
现在天不是应该黑了吗
Shouldn't it be getting dark by now?
是啊  最近夏令时都乱套了
Yeah, this daylight savings thing is all out of whack lately.
见鬼
Damn it.
我的表停了
My watch stopped.
或是坏了什么的
Or is broken or something.
感觉不太对劲
Yeah, something weird's going on.
嗯  不对劲
Yeah. Weird.
不会有好结局  克里夫
Yeah, this isn't gonna end well, Cliff.
蚁群
The ant colonies.
像世界末日临头一样惊慌失措
All jacked up like it was the end of the world.
罗尼  想顺道去餐馆
Hey, Ronnie, you want to swing by the diner,
吃点甜甜圈  喝杯咖啡吗
get some doughnuts, coffee?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
现在吃甜甜圈喝咖啡似乎有点晚了
It seems late for coffee and doughnuts.
也是
I guess so.
这里是总部
This is home base.
收到吗  完毕
Are you guys reading me? Over.
-明迪  -你们没事吧
- Hey, Mindy. - You guys okay out there?
没事  我们只是回去前巡视一周
Yeah, we're just, uh, cruising a bit before we swing on back.
你有什么需要吗
You need anything?
我们可以去趟餐馆
We could, uh, run by the diner,
给你捎点咖啡和甜甜圈
pick you up some coffee and doughnuts.
不用了  谢谢
Negative. Thanks.
不过有件奇怪的事
There is something strange going on, though.
你们有没有注意到...
Have you guys, by any chance, noticed that the...
太阳和...
and the daylight and the...
我觉得新闻...
I think the news report...
喂  喂
Hello, hello.
该死  没信号了
Shit. We lost her.
用你的手机打
Use your cell.
搞笑了
That's funny.
彻底没电了
It's completely dead.
刚充满的
And it was fully charged.
克里夫  要不我们听一下民用广播
Hey, Cliff, should we listen to the civilian radio?
好  开吧
Sure. Go ahead.
♪ 丧尸正如你我 ♪
♪ Oh, the dead don't die ♪
♪ 每日半死不活 ♪
♪ Any more than you or I ♪
这歌好耳熟
That sounds so familiar.
♪ 他们只是活在 ♪
♪ They're just ghosts inside a dream ♪
♪ 虚妄的白日梦中 ♪
♪ Of a life that we don't own ♪
这是什么歌  罗尼
What is that song, Ronnie?
《丧尸未逝》
It's "The Dead Don't Die."
♪ 他们就在你我身边 ♪
♪ They walk around us all the time ♪
斯特吉尔·辛普森唱的
By Sturgill Simpson.
斯特吉尔·辛普森
Sturgill Simpson?
♪ 永远心不在焉 ♪
♪ Never paying any mind ♪
♪ 不管我们活得荒唐 ♪
♪ To the silly lives we lead ♪
为什么听着这么耳熟
Why does it sound so familiar?
因为这是主题曲
Well, 'cause it's the theme song.
♪ 还是死得凄凉 ♪
♪ Or the reaping we've all sown ♪
-主题曲  -是的
- The theme song? - Yeah.
♪ 每个转角都有一杯咖啡 ♪
♪ There's a cup of coffee waiting on every corner ♪
♪ 有一天我们醒来 ♪
♪ Someday we're gonna wake up ♪
♪ 会发现转角不见了 ♪
♪ And find the corners gone ♪
♪ 但是丧尸仍独自 ♪
♪ But the dead will still be walking round ♪
♪ 在这旧世间漫步 ♪
♪ In this old world alone ♪
欢迎来到森特维尔
"一个好地方"
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on ♪
此后殡仪馆
森特维尔青少年拘留中心
月光汽车旅馆
♪ 将有老友漫步 ♪
♪ There'll be old friends walking round ♪
鲍比加油站及杂货店
♪ 在似曾相识小镇 ♪
♪ In a somewhat familiar town ♪
♪ 当你不再盯着手机 ♪
♪ That you saw once ♪
♪ 抬头曾目睹 ♪
♪ When you looked up from the phone ♪
♪ 没人费心打招呼 ♪
♪ Nobody bothers saying hi ♪
♪ 你也大可直接上路 ♪
♪ And you can save all your goodbyes ♪
♪ 别再试图假装 ♪
♪ Stop trying to pretend ♪
让美国变回白种
♪ 你我并不孤独 ♪
♪ That we're all not at home... ♪
我的外带什么时候才能好  弗恩
How much longer until my takeout's ready, Fern?
快了  弗兰克
Be out shortly, Frank.
加热一下就好了
Just heating it up for you.
能把那该死的音乐关掉吗
Would you mind turning off that goddamn music?
该死的斯特吉尔·辛普森
Fucking Sturgill Simpson.
好的
Sure thing.
弗兰克  你为什么一口咬定
So, Frank, what makes you so sure
是隐士鲍勃偷了你的鸡
it's Hermit Bob who stole your chicken?
还能是谁
Well, who the hell else could it be?
那个天杀的长毛疯子
That goddamn hairy lunatic,
像个穴居人一样在林子里生活了这么多年
living out there all these years like a caveman.
就像个幽灵
Like some kind of ghost.
跟阿米什人似的
Might as well be Amish.
可能是狐狸干的  弗兰克
Maybe it was a... a fox, Frank.
我认为鲍勃从没伤害过任何人
I don't think Bob ever hurt anybody.
跟我的鸡说去吧
Yeah, well, tell that to my fucking chickens.
狐狸个球
Fox, my ass.
给你  弗兰克
Here you go, Frank.
咖啡需要打包吗
Want me to put that in a to-go cup for you?
不了  我喝不下去了
Nah, I can't drink any more of that stuff.
对我来说太浓[黑]了
It's too damn black for me.
我是说咖啡太浓
I meant it's too strong.
保重  弗兰克
Take care, Frank.
嗯
Yeah.
特别报道
This special report:
这些活动可能会影响
These activities could possibly be affecting
地球的自转
the Earth's rotation on its axis.
科学家说即使这种平衡
Scientists say even the slightest change
受到一丁点儿破坏都有可能引起
in this balance may already be causing
我们日常白天时长的巨大变化
a dramatic change in our usual hours of daylight.
与此同时  政府官员
Meanwhile, government officials,
以及相关能源公司的负责人表示
as well as the heads of the energy companies involved,
最近对极地广泛采取水力压裂开采
say the recent extensive polar fracking
并没有造成任何明显的影响
has had no discernible consequences whatsoever.
以下是能源部长
Here's what the energy secretary had to say
在晚间记者招待会上的发言
in this evening's press conference.
听着  这些危言耸听者都是危险的骗子
Listen, these alarmists are dangerous liars.
请大家不要轻信
Let's not believe something
某个所谓的科学家的一面之词
just because one so-called scientist says it's true.
极地水力压裂开采为我们的国家创造了
Polar fracking has created fantastic jobs,
大量的就业机会  利润  以及能源
big profits and energy for our great country.
不要忘了当务之急是...
Let's not forget our priori...
你怎么看  弗恩
What you think, Fern?
不知道  汉克
I don't know, Hank.
现在不是应该天黑了吗
Shouldn't it be getting dark out?
森特维尔青少年拘留中心
你可以从这个图表中看到
So, you can see from this diagram
极地水力压裂开采
如果地球略微偏离其自转轴
that if the Earth is pulled even slightly off its axis,
都会产生极端影响
the repercussions could be extreme.
下一时段即将播出
Coming up in the next segment...
我靠  这简直疯了
Holy shit, man, this is crazy.
改变地球自转轴或自转速率
A change in the Earth's rotation or its spin rate?
当然是灾难性的
That'd be catastrophic, for sure.
所有生物周期都会受到影响
All the cycles of the biosphere would be affected.
阳光的自然周期会被扰乱
The natural cycles of sunlight would be disrupted,
植物停止生长  风向规律也会改变
plants wouldn't grow, wind patterns would change,
还有构造活动...
and tectonic activity...
不提这个
Forget about it.
极冠转移意味着...
The polar caps shifting would mean...
我不想说
I don't want to say.
地球彻底毁灭
Total planetary destruction.
真的吗
For real?
别扯了
Shut up.
好了  时间到了  姑娘们
Okay, time's up, girls.
专注  乐观
早就到了
Way up.
杰罗尼莫又跑来女生楼层了
Well, if it isn't Geronimo on the girls' floor again.
你想当女生吗  杰罗尼莫
Do you want to be a girl, Geronimo?
不想
No.
那就赶快回男生区
Well, then get back to the boys' section... now.
丹尼斯
Dennis.
你能送杰罗尼莫回男生区吗
Can you please escort Geronimo back to the boys' section?
这些女生交给我
I'll deal with these girls.
走吧  杰罗尼莫  你知道怎么做
Let's go, Geronimo. You know the drill.
走吧  小丑们
Let's go, you clowns.
笨蛋们该睡觉了
It's bedtime for bozos.
你们俩也一样  走吧
You two ladies, too. Let's go.
不过  能源部长皮勒顿...
Secretary of Energy Pillerton, however...
谢谢
Thank you.
完全否认了这些猜测
fully refutes these speculations,
他坚持声称...
insisting...
再见  鲍比
See you, Bobby.
-太好了  -好了吗  需要袋子吗
- Excellent. - You got it? Need a bag?
-不了  谢谢  -好
- No, thanks. - All right.
-再见  鲍比  -下次见
- Bye, Bobby. - See you guys.
外面还是亮的
Wow, it's still so light out.
好了
Okay. So...
谢谢  欢迎再来
你被监视着
禁止盗窃
出自《指环王》及《霍比特人》
-比尔博·巴金斯  -迪恩
- Bilbo Baggins. - Hey, Dean.
-你好吗  伙计  -最近好吗
- What's up, buddy? - How's things?
下班送货  WUPS
After-hours delivery, WU-PS.
看看这个
Check this out.
有几份《世界奇闻报》
Got some Weird News of the World.
地球偏离自转轴
The Earth off its axis.
这可是坏消息
That's bad news.
这是给你收藏的
This is for you right here, for your collection.
科幻月刊杂志
天呐  《星志》
Oh, man. Starlog.
恐怖漫画杂志
《怪异》
Eerie.
恐怖漫画杂志
《惊悚》第61期
Creepy, number 61.
1974年4月出版
April 1974.
这一期非常罕见  出版时你还没出生
That motherfucker's rare, before you was born and shit.
天呐  我给你点钱
Oh, man. Here, let me give you some money.
不用  算我的
No, that's on me.
-加入你的收藏吧  -谢了  伙计
- Add it to your collection. - Thanks, man.
在这里签收一下
Just give me your Herbie Hancock right here,
我就走了
and I'll be on my way.
空调该修了
They need to fix the AC.
这里热得要命  是吧
You know, it's kind of hot in this motherfucker, huh?
好了
All right.
好的
Okay-dokay.
下周见  弗罗多All right, see you next week, Frodo.
出自《指环王》
迪恩
Hey, Dean.
我在想你介不介意
I was wondering if you wouldn't mind just, uh,
在下次来送货之前分享几句箴言
dropping a little wisdom until the next delivery.
世界很完美
The world is perfect.
要懂得欣赏细节
Appreciate the details.
"世界很完美"
"The world is perfect.
"要懂得欣赏细节"
Appreciate the details."
你们不应该出现在这里
You guys shouldn't be here.
真奇怪
Strange.
美味的牛肝菌
Tasty porcinis.
好
Okay.
免费有线台
有空房
猫咪
Kitty!
晚上好
Good evening.
我是普瓦泽·华雷斯
This is Posie Juarez.
我们打断节目
We interrupt this program
插播森特维尔新闻七台特别报道
for a Centerville 7 News Special Report.
民众反应他们的宠物突然失踪
People are saying their pets have either just disappeared
普瓦泽·华雷斯
哈里斯维尔残忍袭击事件
或表现得惊惶不安  有攻击性
or are acting unusually skittish and aggressive.
下面是来自哈里斯维尔的报道
Here's a report from Harrisville.
你看看
Look at this.
我就是找不到我的猫  她叫彩虹
I mean, I just couldn't find my cat, Rainbow.
等我终于找到她了
And when I finally did find her,
她居然在房子底下
she was under the house.
她以前从来没有这样过
She's never done that before.
平时她不是这样的
She's not usually like that.
她很温柔...
She's very gentle and...
真奇怪  你们去哪了
That's so strange. Where are you guys?
她的眼中充满狂野
too, and she had this wild look in her eye,
等我好不容易把她弄出来了
and when I finally tried to pull her out,
她就像野兽一样  把我抓得遍体鳞伤
she scratched me all to shreds, like a wild animal.
太可怕了  我知道...
That's so creepy. I knew...
切回来了
We're back?
大家好
Hello.
太奇怪了  似乎各地都在发生这种情况
That is strange, and it seems to be happening all over.
十一点会有更多报道
We'll have more reports at 11:00.
这里是森特维尔新闻七台
But for now, this is Posie Juarez
普瓦泽·华雷斯为您报道
for Centerville 7 News.
请注意安全
Stay safe...
并保持警惕
and keep your eyes open.
拉姆斯菲尔德
Rumsfeld.
拉姆斯菲尔德  过来
Rumsfeld. Here, boy.
你到底去哪了
Where the hell are you?
该死的狗
Goddamn dog.
拉姆斯菲尔德  你在外面吗
Rumsfeld? You out here?
拉姆斯菲尔德  你在那干什么
Rumsfeld, what you doing over there?
快给我进来
Get your ass inside.
快点  蠢狗
Come on, stupid.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
该死的
Goddamn it.
我操
Holy shit.
谁他妈偷走了我的牛
Who stole my fucking cows?
我的鸡都去哪了
Where the hell are my chickens?
弗兰克的牛
Frank's cows.
去森林里吧  女士们
Into the woods, ladies.
欢迎来到我的世界
Welcome to my world.
该死的  马洛里
Damn it, Mallory.
就算死了你身上都有霞多丽白葡萄酒的气味
Even dead, you reek of chardonnay.
廉价的霞多丽
Cheap chardonnay.
她看上去如何
How's she looking?
反正她不会再衰老了
Well, she's not getting any older.
这个餐馆的咖啡
The diner sure makes
绝对是世界第一  对吧
the world's best coffee, doesn't it?
但是你怎么这么晚了还在喝
Yeah, but how can you drink it so late?
-不会睡不着吗  -不会  我的睡眠如婴儿一般
- Won't it keep you up? - No, I sleep like a baby.
除了办公室里有一具尸体在等我的时候
Except maybe when I know there's a corpse waiting for me at work.
对了
Oh, y-yeah.
克里夫  拉特罗布的验尸官
Cliff, is the coroner from Latrobe
明天会来接她吗
gonna pick her up tomorrow?
独自守着马洛里逐渐腐败的尸体
It's getting a little creepy being here alone
感觉越来越吓人了
with Mallory decomposing in there.
明天他们应该会来接走她
Yeah, they're supposed to come pick her up tomorrow morning.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
为什么不能送她去殡仪馆
I don't know why she can't be over at the funeral home.
因为她要埋在拉特罗布的波特墓园
'Cause she's going to Potter's Field in Latrobe.
而且我们新来的不同寻常的殡葬员
And 'cause our new unusual undertaker,
温斯顿女士手上已经有两个被闪电劈死的
Ms. Winston, has got those two golfers
高尔夫球手了  罗根夫妇
that were struck by lightning... the Logans.
谢谢  罗尼
Thanks, Ronnie.
没这个必要  不过
It's not really necessary, but...
我可以送你回家吗  明迪
Can I, uh, drive you home, Mindy?
同样没必要  罗尼  你知道我是开车来的
Also not necessary, Ronnie. You know I have my car here.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
-普锐斯开着如何  -挺好
- How is the Prius running? - Fine.
你那辆Smart挤得下两个人吗
Can you even fit two people in that little Smart car of yours?
当然了  两个人刚刚好
Well, yeah. Holds two nicely.
太阳还不下山让我很不踏实
This daylight thing is bothering me.
真奇怪
It's strange.
我能说什么呢
Well, what can I say?
最近这个世界是挺奇怪的
The world is kind of strange lately.
确实
Yeah, it sure is.
要我说的话  不会有好结局
If you ask me, this whole thing is gonna end badly.
你到底是什么意思  罗尼
So, what exactly do you mean, Ronnie?
说不好
Don't know.
只是有种预感
Just a feeling, I guess.
强烈的预感
Strong feeling.
天呐
Oh, boy.
克里夫  你一个人值夜班没问题吗
You okay doing the whole night shift alone, Cliff?
嗯  我可以睡一会儿
Yeah, I can take a nap.
我可以躺在隔壁牢房里
I mean, I can just lie down in that other cell
挨着老马洛里
next to old Mallory.
天啊
Oh, God.
挨着她的尸体吗
Next to her... her dead body?
或许会回忆起一些往事
Might bring back some old memories.
明天见
See you guys tomorrow.
-再见  克里夫  -明天见  警长
- See you, Cliff. - Yeah, see you tomorrow, Chief.
"不会有好结局"
"This is all gonna end badly."
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我从孩提时代就认识马洛里·奥布莱恩了
I knew Mallory O'Brien since I was a kid.
信不信由你
And believe it or not,
她当年也美艳极了
sh-she was a pretty young thing, too.
拜托
Please.
不好意思  但是能摆脱那个老酒鬼真是太好了
Sorry, but good riddance to that drunken old goat.
别这么说  弗恩
Well, I-I-I don't know, Fern.
天呐  我得走了
Geez, I got to get up out of here.
我明天一早还要去五金店
I-I got to, uh, get to the hardware store early tomorrow morning.
二位女士  我们明天再见
I'm looking forward to seeing you ladies tomorrow.
保重  汉克
Take care, Hank.
晚安  汉克  祝你好梦
Good night, Hank. Sweet dreams.
汉克真是个绅士
Hank is such a gentleman.
没错
Sure is.
我还是赶紧开始打扫吧
Well, I better get started cleaning here.
听着  莉莉
Listen, Lily.
我一直特别想问你那个外国女人的事
I've been dying to ask you about that new foreign woman
就是那个接管殡仪馆的人
that took over the funeral home.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
她叫泽尔达·温斯顿
Her name is Zelda Winston.
她确实很古怪
And she's strange, for sure.
她那双眼睛非常奇怪
And she's got these, like, really weird eyes,
好像能直接看透你
like she's, like, looking right through you.
不过她付钱很大方
She pays me really well, though.
泽尔达  这是什么鬼名字
Zelda. What-what kind of name is that?
不知道
I don't know.
她大概是爱尔兰或苏格兰人吧
She's probably, like, Irish or Scottish or whatever.
而且她说话的腔调也很怪
And she talks really funny, though,
所以有时候说什么我也听不懂
so I don't always get it right.
不过我喜欢泽尔达这个名字
But I like the name Zelda.
让我想起了泽尔达·菲茨杰拉德
It reminds me of, um, Zelda Fitzgerald.
那是谁
Who's that?
《了不起的盖茨比》的作者的老婆
That's Great Gatsby's wife.
那又是谁
And who's that?
1920年代一个超有钱的人
That's the really rich guy from the 1920s.
罗伯特·雷德福演的那个人
The Robert Redford guy.
不管怎样  她接管以后
Well, anyway, so what's it like over there
那些密室里情况如何
in those secret rooms since she took over?
里面有很可怕的密室
Well, there's these, like, really creepy back rooms,
所有的尸体都锁在那里面
you know, where they, like, keep all the stiffs.
旁边放着一个巨大的金佛
And then next to that, there's this big golden Buddha.
什么玩意
A what, now?
一个巨大的闪闪发光的金佛
There's a big, shiny, golden Buddha.
然后架子上还放了
And then there's these, like,
几把很古老的武士刀
old-looking samurai swords on a rack.
真的吗
Really?
阿弥陀佛
Amituofo.
真奇怪
That's peculiar.
你们别乱动  好吗
Now, stay put, will you?
森特维尔警局
怎么了  丽芙
What is it, Liv?
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
应该没事
I guess so.
我刚才有种很可怕的感觉
I just got this creepy feeling.
你可能只是做噩梦了
You were probably just having a bad dream.
嗯  应该是吧
Yeah, guess so.
做噩梦了
A bad dream.
没事的  接着睡吧
It's okay. Just go back to sleep.
谢了  斯特拉
Thanks, Stell.
有害的月球震动
Toxic lunar vibrations.
营业中
好了  亲爱的  我完事了
All right, honey, I'm done.
我把你的钱放在这里
I'm leaving your money here.
我要走了  莉莉
I'm out of here, Lil.
好的  弗恩  明天见
Okay, Fern. See you tomorrow.
除非我先见到你
Not if I see you first.
真幽默
Very funny.
不好意思  我们打烊了
Excuse me, we're closed.
你怎么回事
What... what happened to you?
莉莉
Lily!
离我远点  你这个混蛋
Get the fuck away from me, you little motherfucker!
我他妈杀了你
Oh, I'll fucking kill you!
我要把这个拖把塞你菊花里  混账东西
I'll shove this mop up your fucking ass, motherfucker!
离我远点
Get the fuck away from me!
咖啡
Coffee.
森特维尔警局
森特维尔警局  我是罗伯特森警长
Centerville Police Department. This is Chief Robertson.
汉克  什么事
Hi, Hank. What's up?
已经六点半了吗
Is it really 6:30?
什么
What?
在餐馆吗
At the diner?
跟我在电话里说的一样  克里夫
Like I said on the phone, Cliff,
弗恩通常会早到
often, Fern gets here early,
所以我想着也许能
and so I thought I might
买杯咖啡带走  然后就看到了这一幕
get some coffee to go, and-and then this.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我看到她们了
I saw them.
弗恩和莉莉
Fern and Lily.
天呐
Oh, man.
到底是什么东西干的
Wh-What the hell was it?
一只野生动物  还有好几只野生动物
A wild animal? Uh, several wild animals?
我不知道
I don't know.
但不管是什么  它连咖啡壶都打碎了
But whatever it was, it even smashed the coffeepots.
真恶心
Yuck.
老天爷啊  克里夫
Jesus Christ, Cliff.
是什么东西干的  一只野生动物
What the heck was it, a wild animal?
还是好几只野生动物
Several wild animals?
我也是这么说的
That's exactly what I said.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
弗恩把花圃照料得真棒
Fern's really done wonders with these flower beds.
让这个地方增色不少  对吗
Really perks up the place, huh?
怎么了
What?
-出什么事了  -天呐  明迪
- What happened? - God, Mindy.
我觉得你最好不要去看
I don't think you want to see this.
对  对  确实不该看的
No, no, I didn't need to see that.
是一只野生动物干的吗
Was it a wild animal?
还是好几只野生动物
Or several wild animals?
克里夫  里面真的是弗恩和莉莉吗
Cliff, is that really Fern and Lily in there?
不
No.
生前是弗恩和莉莉  但现在...
That was Fern and Lily, but now...
你这里需要我吗
Do you need me here?
也许你可以帮忙控制人流
Maybe you could help out with crowd control.
好了  大伙  能请你们离开吗
Okay, folks, can you move it along now, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
我不敢相信
I can't believe it.
天呐  罗尼  这真的太可怕了
God, Ronnie. This is really awful.
这可能是我此生见过的最可怕的事
Maybe the worst thing I've ever seen.
是啊  肯定的
Yeah. Sure is.
我
I...
我得走了
I-I got to go.
你觉得是怎么回事
So, what are you thinking?
你真想知道吗
You... you really want to know?
我觉得是僵尸
I'm thinking zombies.
什么
What?
你明白的  僵尸
You know, zombies.
食尸鬼
Ghouls.
活死人
The undead.
你是...
Are you...
你是想告诉我
You're trying to tell me...
你觉得这是僵尸干的吗
you're thinking zombies did this?
对
Yup.
杰克  你能用手机查查
Hey, Jack, will you check your phone
-我们现在在哪吗  -好
- and see where we are exactly? - Yeah.
天呐
Oh, man.
在这里收不到信号
I'm not getting any reception out here.
天呐  不知为何
Geez, I don't even know
我都不知道我的手机还能不能用
if my phone's working, for some reason.
我试试广播
Let me try the radio.
广播又能用了
It's working again, so...
他们大错特错
I mean, they're absolutely wrong.
我们非常清楚极地水力压裂开采
We know very well that polar fracking
对这个国家意义重大
has been great for this country.
在我看来  这些反对者
In my opinion, these naysayers
-应该搬去其它地方  -我不听这个
- should just move to somewhere else... - I'm not listening to this.
在那里他们不用...
where they don't have to...
♪ 清晨街头空无一物 ♪
♪ And the streets look so empty in the morning ♪
《丧尸未逝》
"The Dead Don't Die."
我很爱这首歌
I love this song.
♪ 无人再需 ♪
♪ There'll be no one out at night ♪
♪ 夜灯引路 ♪
♪ For the lights to shine down on ♪
♪ 但是丧尸仍独自 ♪
♪ But the dead will still be walking round ♪
♪ 在这旧世间漫步 ♪
♪ In this old world alone ♪
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on ♪
♪ 亲人逝去  命赴黄泉 ♪
♪ Hearts break when loved ones journey on ♪
♪ 如此一想  心碎难捱 ♪
♪ At the thought that they're now forever gone ♪
♪ 所以我们告诉自己 ♪
♪ So we tell ourselves ♪
♪ 他们一直都在我们身边 ♪
♪ They're all still around us all the time ♪
谢谢
Thanks.
♪ 已逝却未被遗忘 ♪
♪ Gone but not forgotten ♪
♪ 只余回忆心中藏 ♪
♪ Just memories left behind ♪
见鬼  我们得停下来加油
Oh, shit, you guys. We have to stop and get gas.
看  那边有加油站的指示牌
Look. Gas sign right there.
加油站
♪ 但是丧尸仍独自 ♪
♪ But the dead will still be walking round ♪
♪ 在这旧世间漫步 ♪
♪ In this old world alone... ♪
好  下次再来  好吗
Okay, cool. Come back soon, okay?
再见  鲍比
See you, Bobby.
经典恐怖节目Ghoulardi中的台词
一病不起  伙计们
Stay sick, guys.
死尸变蓝  鲍比
Turn blue, Bobby.
小孩  你们好吗
Hey, kids, how's it going?
咬我啊
Eat me.
这个地方可真奇妙
This place is a trip.
是啊
Sure is.
你好
Hi.
T恤不错
Nice shirt.
1922年德国吸血鬼题材恐怖片
-《诺斯费拉图》  -是的
- Nosferatu. - Yeah.
非常酷
It's really cool.
谢谢
Thanks.
是我自己做的
I make 'em.
看这个  地球偏离了自转轴
How about that? Earth off its axis.
世界末日
End of the world.
吃人的僵尸
Flesh-eating zombies.
你们这附近有很多僵尸吗
You get a lot of zombies around here?
我觉得要看情况
That depends, I guess.
所以油钱
So... so, about the gas.
你们是想付现金还是刷卡
You want to pay cash or credit?
给  弗罗多
Here you go, Frodo.
好  谢谢
Cool. Thanks.
你刚刚...
Did you, uh...
你刚刚是管我叫弗罗多吗
Did you just call me Frodo?
我有吗
Did I?
镇上有汽车旅馆吗
Is there a motel in town?
有的  有一家就在...
Yeah, there is one just down the...
每张12美元  丧尸未逝
这张专辑很棒
That's a really good CD.
斯特吉尔·辛普森  《丧尸未逝》
Sturgill Simpson, "The Dead Don't Die."
我知道  我很爱这首歌
Yeah, I know. I love this song.
好不好
Is it nice?
-什么  -汽车旅馆
- What? - The motel.
对的  还不错
Oh, yeah. It's, uh... it's kind of cool.
是传统的那种
It's one of those old-school ones.
就像传统的恐怖片
Like in old-school horror movies,
比方说像《惊魂记》里那种分开来的平房吗
with, like... like in Psycho with the separated bungalows?
《惊魂记》中的贝茨旅馆
The Bates Motel in Psycho
不是分开来的"小小的平房"
was not separated into "little bungalows."
好吧
All right.
专辑是十二美元  汽水两美元
That's 12 for the CD and two dollars for the soda.
给
Here you go.
-不用找了  -多谢
- You can just keep the change. - Thanks. Oh, cool.
顺便说一句  这辆车太酷了
That's a super cool ride, by the way.
美国著名导演兼编剧  擅长恐怖题材
非常有乔治·罗梅罗风格
Very, uh, George Romero.
是啊  这是经典车型
Yeah, it's a classic.
你的电影知识令人惊叹
Your film knowledge is impressive.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
鲍比
Bobby.
鲍比·威金斯
Bobby Wiggins.
叫什么  鲍比·巴金斯吗
What's that? Bobby Baggins?
不  威金斯
No, Wiggins.
我叫佐伊
I'm Zoe.
谢谢  鲍比
Thanks, Bobby.
联调局探员要来查这个案子吗  这
Will the Feds be brought in on this? It's...
这太奇怪了
it's really weird.
我明白了
I see.
但是奥布莱恩小姐
But Miss O'Brien...
还要在我们这里放一夜吗
so she has to stay with us another night?
天呐
Oh, God.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
你好  温斯顿女士
Hello, Ms. Winston.
你好  明妮瓦·莫里森警官
Hello, Officer Minerva Morrison.
叫我泽尔达就好
Do call me Zelda.
好的  没问题
Yeah, okay, sure.
你收到惨案的消息了吗
You've been informed of the tragedy?
我收到了
I have.
我想请问遗体
Am I to understand that the remains
会被送到此后殡仪馆
will be brought to The Ever After Funeral Home
由我来整理准备吗
for my preparations?
不  不需要
No, that won't be necessary.
联调局已经取走了遗体
The Feds have already collected the remains.
他们把遗体带出这个县了
They've brought them out of the county.
我明白了
I see.
还有什么需要吗
Is there anything else I can do?
是的
Yes.
我确实有一个不相关的问题
I do have an unrelated question.
向我开炮
Shoot.
"开炮"
"Shoot"?
我的意思是问吧
I mean ask me.
好
Oh, yes.
你们是一对吗
Are you, by any chance, a couple?
你和那个外表英俊的警官
You and the physically attractive one?
你是说年轻的那个吗
You mean the younger one?
皮特森警官
Officer Peterson?
我说的就是罗纳德·皮特森警官
That's the one I mean... Officer Ronald Peterson.
其实不是
Well, actually, no.
你为什么问这个  泽尔达
Why do you ask, Zelda?
只是在收集本地信息
Just accumulating local information.
好吧
Okay.
老天爷
Dear Jesus.
这实在太可怕了
I mean, that's absolutely horrible.
是谁或是什么东西
I mean, who or what is-is-is
犯下了这些罪行...
per-perpetrating these... these...
你们好吗
What's going on?
车不错
Nice car.
68年的庞蒂亚克勒芒斯
'68 Pontiac LeMans.
是啊  真漂亮
Yeah. It's a beauty, huh?
这是我们朋友的好车
It's our friend's totally rad ride.
经典车型
It's a classic.
祝你们愉快
Have a good one.
回见
Later.
伙计们  我好饿
Guys, I'm so hungry.
我也是  我们去吃饭吧
Same. Let's eat.
我问问
I'll ask.
-车不错  -谢谢
- Nice car. - Thank you.
这附近有餐馆或者餐厅吗
Do you guys know if there's a diner or restaurant nearby?
抱歉
Sorry.
镇上的唯一一家餐馆无限期关门了
The only diner in town is closed, indefinitely.
真遗憾
Well, that's unfortunate.
不过办公室旁边
But we, uh, have several vending machines
有几台自动贩卖机  里面有零食
containing snacks, uh, right over by the office.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
你有三美元的零钱吗
Do you have change for three dollars?
我有
Yeah, I do.
我喜欢你的警徽
I like your badge.
谢谢
Th... Thank you.
这是...
That's, uh...
-应该够了  -好的
- That-that should be good. - Oh, okay.
-谢谢  -不  不用
- Thanks. - Oh, no, no.
-你都拿走吧  -可以吗
- You can, you can have it. - Yeah?
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
他们刚刚入住
They just checked in.
大城市来的潮人
Hipsters from the big city.
-是吗  -是的
-Yeah? - Yeah.
我推测他们是从匹兹堡来的
My educated guess would be Pittsburgh.
他们有那种城市范儿
They got that urban style, you know.
那是俄亥俄州的车牌
Well, those plates are from Ohio,
所以我推测是从克利夫兰来的
so my educated guess would be Cleveland.
克利夫兰
Cleveland.
没错  克利夫兰
Yeah, Cleveland.
谢了
Thanks.
没事  谢谢
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
那女孩有墨西哥血统
That girl's part Mexican.
是吗
Really?
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
我对墨西哥人情有独钟
I have an affinity for Mexicans.
他们是我最喜欢的人种
They're, like, my favorite people.
我喜欢墨西哥  我去过两次
I love Mexico. I've been down there twice.
好吧  罗尼
Okay, Ronnie,
那请你去告诉他们
then you should be the one to inform them
如果他们要在森特维尔过夜
that if they're gonna spend the night in Centerville,
那就不要出门
to not go out
把门锁好  去吧
and to keep their hotel room door locked. Okay.
克里夫  有件事...
You know, Cliff, uh...
我知道可能不是特别要紧
I know this isn't important comparatively, uh,
但是我的猫全都不见了
but, uh, all of my cats are gone.
一般它们都是待在屋里的
And-and, normally, they-they, uh, just stay inside.
我很遗憾  丹尼
Well, I'm sorry about that, Danny.
它们可能是藏起来了
They could be hiding.
现在一切都很不正常
Nothing is happening normally right now.
-嗯  - 他们什么反应
- Yeah. - How did they react?
他们说  "我听说你们说这里有很多僵尸"
They said, "I heard you had a lot of zombies around here,"
然后就笑起来了
and then they laughed.
可恶的潮人  就喜欢嘲讽
Infernal hipsters with their irony.
赫尔曼·麦尔维尔著
白鲸
麦尔维尔
Melville.
"无数凡人的无名苦难"
"Nameless miseries of the numberless mortals."
外面看起来一切正常
Well, everything looks normal out there.
嗯
Yeah.
但是发生的事听起来就像是
But what happened sounds like the start of
-恐怖电影的序章  -确实
- a gruesome horror film. - Sure does.
真的一点都不好玩  杰罗尼莫
Really, really not funny, Geronimo.
你们听说餐馆发生的可怕谋杀案了吗
You guys hear about those grisly murders at the diner?
嗯  我们正在聊这个
Yeah. Just talking about them.
可怕
Creepy.
我一直在听广播
I've been listening to the radio,
肯定是活死人干的
and I'm sure it's the undead, yo.
地球由于水力压裂开采偏离了自转轴
Reanimated by the Earth being thrown off its axis
于是死人复活了
from the polar fracking.
你想说什么
What are you saying?
我想说
I'm saying...
僵尸末日要来了  宝贝
full-on zombie apocalypse, baby.
很快它们就会成群结队地出现
Soon, there'll be hordes of them.
-杰罗尼莫  -靠
- Geronimo. - Shit.
你又想失去特权了是吧
Do you want to lose your privileges again?
不是  警官
No, sir.
那就走吧
Then let's go.
不可理喻
Unbelievable.
森特维尔墓园
克里夫  他们为什么要把
Cliff, why'd they used to separate
小孩的坟墓跟大人的坟墓分开
the children's graves from the adults'?
不知道  可能是十九世纪的习俗吧
Don't know. Some kind of a 19th-century thing.
感觉这主意不怎么样
Seems like a bad idea somehow.
我们到底来这里找什么  僵尸吗
Yeah. So, what exactly are we looking for here? Zombies?
看这边
Look over here.
还有一个
Here's another one.
老天  一定不会有好结局
Oh, man. This isn't gonna end well.
该死的
Goddamn it.
食尸鬼
Ghouls.
这是复活的活死人
This is undead, reanimated,
吃人肉的僵尸
full-on, flesh-eating zombie shit.
毫无疑问
No question.
我本来该退休了
I was supposed to retire.
-两年前就该退休了  -我知道
- Two years ago. - I know.
-为什么不呢  -什么
- Why didn't you? - What?
为什么不两年前退休
Retire two years ago.
我们这是在即兴表演吗
Are we improvising here?
不是  随便问问
No, I was just asking.
反正我可能也知道答案
But I probably know the answer anyway.
可能吧
Probably. Yeah.
我们的计划是赶在天黑前
So, is our plan to continue to inform people
继续通知人们有僵尸出没吗
about the zombie danger before it gets dark?
老天  罗尼
Oh, God, Ronnie.
应该是吧
I guess so.
那我们刚刚经过了农夫米勒的家
Because we passed Farmer Miller's place a little while ago.
我们要去通知他吗
Do we need to inform him?
去他的农夫米勒
Fuck Farmer Miller.
真要这样
Really?
他也是森特维尔的居民啊
He is a citizen of Centerville.
你说得对
You're right.
让明迪打电话通知他吧
We'll have Mindy call him.
好的
Oh, okay.
罗尼  该怎么杀死一个僵尸呢
So, Ronnie, how the fuck do you kill a zombie?
你得把头砍下来
Well, you got to kill the head.
-"把头砍下来"  -对
- "Kill the head." - Yeah.
用什么手段都行  把头砍下来
By any means necessary, kill the head.
斩首  这是杀死它们的唯一方法
Decapitate. It's the only way to kill them.
老天
Jesus.
唯一能够真正阻止僵尸的方法
And that's really the only way to stop zombies,
就是砍掉它的头  汉克
is to kill the head, Hank.
我知道这很吓人  但是必须把头完全砍下来
I know it's gruesome, but complete decapitation.
不管你是用弯刀  钢丝
Doesn't matter if you use a-a machete, steel wire,
还是大剪刀  无所谓
hedge clippers, whatever.
只要切断脊柱就行  懂吗
Just as long as the spinal cord is severed, right?
头也要砍下来
And the head... is cut off.
就这样  死个彻底
And that's it. De-animated.
杀死死人的唯一方法
Only way to kill the dead:
把头砍下来
kill the head.
等等  鲍比
Wait, Bobby.
我不确定那就是僵尸
I-I'm not so sure it was zombies.
你说它们吃了莉莉和弗恩的肉
You said they ate Lily and Fern's flesh.
一般而言  它们会吃大脑
Usually, they go for the brains.
这有点不寻常  但是
It's unusual, but...
它还是会吃人
it's still cannibals, man.
绝对是僵尸  好吗
Definitely zombies. Okay?
汉克  你可以相信我
Hank, you can trust me.
我看过几乎所有的僵尸电影
I've seen almost every zombie film ever made.
僵尸要来了  我们得做好准备
This is zombie shit going down, and we got to get prepared.
我没法思考了
I don't know what to think anymore.
汉克  子弹
Hank, the shells.
对
Oh, yeah.
小心无大错
Better safe than sorry.
你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
小心无大错
Safe than sorry.
把头砍下来就行
Just kill the head.
东布雷迪郊区的这个居民区还发生了
Several other shocking and brutal attacks
几起令人震惊的残忍袭击事件
occurred in this residential neighborhood just outside East Brady.
画面极其血腥恐怖
The images are just too gruesome
目前无法播出
to broadcast at this time,
特别报道
警方表示  这些受害者
and police are saying that it almost looked like
看起来像是被一只或几只
the victims were attacked by a wild animal
野生动物所袭击
or perhaps several wild animals.
沃克镇
东布雷迪
黛西镇
布朗斯维尔
森特维尔
警方提供了这一地区的地图  标明了...
Police did provide this map showing where these...
该死  我的手表坏了
Goddamn it, my watch doesn't fucking work.
这是我刚买的  花了好多钱
I just got it. It's mad expensive.
天啊  这太疯狂了
Holy shit, dude, this is insane.
也许加油站那个哈利波特
Maybe that Harry Potter guy at the gas station
不是在开玩笑
wasn't kidding, man.
什么  他说什么了
What, about-about what?
就是说附近有僵尸的那些话
About there being zombies around here.
一点都不好笑
That's not even funny.
别开玩笑了  这真的很诡异
Don't joke. It's really, really creepy.
当局提醒所有居民
Authorities are warning all citizens
待在室内  并确保锁好门窗
to stay inside and keep all doors and windows locked and secured.
扎克  把门锁上好吗
Zack, lock the door, will you?
-好的  -这里是
- Got you. - But for now,
森特维尔新闻七台  波西·华雷斯为您报道
this is Posie Juarez for Centerville 7 News.
请注意安全并保持警惕
Stay safe and keep your eyes open.
猫咪
Kitties!
你们在哪呢
Where are you guys?
猫咪
Kitties!
到底是怎么了
What in the name of...
猫都不见了
Cats are gone.
已经两天没见到或听到小鸟了
Haven't seen or heard a bird in two days.
这么早天就黑了
It's already night out.
才五点
It's 5:00.
亲爱的上帝  保佑我们
Dear Lord in Heaven, help us.
免费有线电视
Free cable.
没错  免费...
It's free ca...
谢天谢地你们回来了
Thank God you guys are back.
天啊  克里夫  我们真的需要这些吗
Jesus, Cliff, do we really need all this stuff?
这些是干什么用的
What's all this for?
我们去了五金商店
We went by the hardware store.
然后就如你所见了
You know what happens.
汉克和加油站的那个霍比特人鲍比
Hank and that hobbit kid Bobby from the gas station
已经把自己锁起来了
have locked themselves in over there.
他们想说服其他人一起加入
They tried to convince other citizens to join them,
但是没有成功
but with no success.
为什么  发生了什么
Why? What's happening?
是爆发传染病了吗
Is it some sort of epidemic or what?
是僵尸
It's zombies.
-你在说什么  -就是活死人
- What are you saying? - Well, it's the undead.
它们复活了
They've been reanimated.
因为地球偏离了自转轴
Caused by the Earth having been pulled off its axis,
因为极地水力压裂开采
caused by the polar fracking.
但是当局和能源公司
But the authorities and energy people
一直说这不是真的啊
keep saying that's not true.
真的假的
Really?
天啊
Oh, my God.
-她还活着  -不
- She's alive? - No.
她死了  只是变成了活死人
She's not. She's just undead.
霞多丽
Chardonnay.
我去  她刚刚是不是说了"霞多丽"
Holy shit. Did she just say "chardonnay"?
是的
Yeah, she did.
小心点  孩子们
Look out, kids.
你好啊  马洛里
Hey, little Mallory.
霞多丽
Chardonnay.
我来吧  克里夫
I got this, Cliff.
霞多丽
Chardonnay.
刚才砍得不错
Those are some pretty good cuts.
你在小联盟赛打过棒球  对吗
You played some minor league ball, didn't you?
1A级而已
Well, um, a little Class A.
很久以前的事了
It-it was a long time ago.
明迪  记住把头砍下来就行了
Mindy, just remember to kill the head.
好
Okay.
把头砍下来  行
Kill the head. Okay.
罗尼  处理一下
Ronnie, take this thing out of here.
好的  警长
You got it, Chief.
真漂亮
That's very nice.
非常漂亮
Very nice, indeed.
你看起来美极了
You look gorgeous.
你们两个可以
You two could have been
携手称霸高尔夫俱乐部了  没问题
the king and queen of the golf club, so you could.
哎哟喂
Oh, my.
怎么搞的
What's this?
你俩是串通一气的吧
Are you in this together?
这样真的很不合适
I mean, this is really inappropriate.
我的天啊
Oh, good grief.
死人今天就是不想死  是吧
So, the dead just don't want to die today. Is that it?
太可惜了
That's a shame.
我给他俩化得那么好看
I had them looking so bonny.
又怎么了
What is it now?
谁在门外
Who's there?
该死
Shit.
你他妈是谁
Who the fuck are you,
你想怎样
and what do you want?
快他妈放开
Get the fuck...
该死
Shit.
我杀了他
I killed him.
太诡异了
That was weird.
糖果
Candy.
-糖果  -饮料
- Candy. - Snapple.
饮料
Snapple.
士力架
Snickers.
-冰棒  -士力架
- Popsicle. - Snickers.
冰棒
Popsicle.
玩具
Toys.
彩虹糖
Skittles.
玩具
Toys.
WiFi
Wi-Fi.
蓝牙
Bluetooth.
Siri
Siri.
-焦虑药  -止痛药
- Xanax. - Oxy.
安眠药
Ambien.
药房
止痛药
Oxy.
吉他
Guitar.
五金店
-工具  -钻头
- Tools. - Drill.
砂光机
Sander.
工具
Tools.
不要  拜托
No. Come on.
好了  好了  要命了
Okay, okay. Holy shit.
我们得干掉他们
We need to mow them down.
鲍比  该死
Bobby. Shit.
这个我来  汉克
I got this one, Hank.
该死
Shit.
鲍比
Bobby!
砍头  汉克
The head, Hank!
我把头砍下来了
I killed the head.
怎么回事  真的假的
What the fuck? Is this for real?
别出声
Quiet!
快滚开
Get the fuck off me!
-操  -天啊
- Fuck! - Holy shit!
白痴
Shithead!
救救我
Save me!
-什么  别去  -你要干什么  停下
- What? No! - What are you doing? Stop!
快滚开
Get the fuck off me!
去储藏室
Closet.
-操  -该死的白痴
- Fuck! - Fucking shithead!
暴力的...
...violent...
一系列的古怪袭击事件逐渐升级
Reports of these bizarre attacks are escalating,
森特维尔警局
类似事件全国各地都有发生
with incidents occurring sporadically across the country
而我们现在了解到  应该是全球各地
and, as we're now learning, uh, across the globe.
据称这些暴力掠夺者
You see, these violent marauders
先是在墓园聚集
have apparently first been gathering in cemeteries,
然后分散至城镇及郊区
then dispersing into towns and suburbs,
但也有报道称...
while other reports suggest...
真好
Great.
现在连广播都坏了
Now even the radio's dead.
终于清静了
Good riddance.
伙计们
Guys...
我们是不是应该互相安慰说
shouldn't we be telling each other
一切都会没事的
that it's all gonna be okay?
一切都会像噩梦一样烟消云散
That this will all go away, like a bad dream?
罗尼
Ronnie?
天  明迪  我不确定我能说出来
Gee, Mindy, I'm not sure I can say that.
克里夫
Cliff?
拜托了
Please?
一切都会没事的  明迪
It's all gonna be okay, Mindy.
或许这一切都会像噩梦一样烟消云散
Maybe it'll all just go away, like a bad dream.
深表怀疑
I doubt it.
七  八
Seven and eight.
月光汽车旅馆
现在两边都做八下
Now do both for eight.
用力  用力  对
And push. And push. Yeah.
克利夫兰
Cleveland.
什么鬼
What the...
这才叫黑压压一群乌鸦
Now, that's what I call a murder of crows.
我去  她的刀法真犀利  对吧
Darn, she's really good with that thing, isn't she?
的确如此
She sure is.
她好奇怪
She's strange.
-她是苏格兰人  -她是苏格兰人吗
- She's Scottish. - She's Scottish?
开门让她进来
Let's unbolt the door and get her in here.
非常感谢  罗纳德·皮特森警官
Thank you very much, Officer Ronald Peterson.
克里夫德·罗伯特森警长
Chief Clifford Robertson.
明妮瓦·莫里森警官
Officer Minerva Morrison.
你的行动计划具体是什么呢
What exactly is your plan of action,
克里夫德·罗伯特森警长
Chief Clifford Robertson?
这个嘛
Well...
现在平静一些了
It's a little quieter now.
我认为  我觉得我们应该开着巡逻车
I-I think, I guess we should just get in the patrol car...
反正我们之中得有人...在社区内巡逻
some of us, anyway... and, uh, patrol the community.
毕竟这是我们的职责
After all, that is our job.
我不要留在这里
I'm not staying here.
我觉得大家应该一起行动
I-I think we should all go together.
嗯  你说得对
Well, I guess you're right.
我可以留在这里  监控事态发展
I could stay here and monitor things,
如果这样有帮助的话
if that would help.
我对自己抵御活死人的能力十分自信
I'm quite confident of my ability to defend myself against the undead.
我看得出来
Well, I-I can see that.
但是你会操作我们的警务无线电和电脑吗
But, uh, can you operate the police radio and our computer?
会的
Oh, aye.
别担心
No bother.
当然会
Certainly.
如果还没坏的话
Yeah, if it still works.
我不确定
I don't know.
这有些不同寻常  不是吗  克里夫
That would be a little unusual, wouldn't it, Cliff?
特殊情况特殊处理  不是吗
Well, this is a highly unusual situation we're in, is it not,
克里夫德·罗伯特森警长
Chief Clifford Robertson?
或许我们稍后可以在墓园汇合
Perhaps we could all meet up again in a wee while in the cemetery.
好的  我觉得没问题
Yeah, it's okay. I guess it's okay.
我们出发吧
Let's go, guys.
巡逻车上还有些武器
We've got some more weapons in the patrol car.
不好意思  罗纳德·皮特森警官
Excuse me, Officer Ronald Peterson.
我可以请求借用
Might I request that I have
你的交通工具吗
the use of your own personal vehicle?
好的
Okay.
《星球大战》
Star Wars.
绝佳的科幻片
Excellent fiction.
是那辆...
It's the, uh...
红色的敞篷Smart吗
Red convertible Smart car?
是的
Yes.
路上小心
Mind how you go.
慢一点  克里夫
Slow down a second, Cliff.
不好意思
Excuse me.
棒
Yes.
把头砍下来
Kill the head.
他们会被生前熟悉的事物所吸引
They gravitate towards things they did when they were alive.
嗯
Yeah.
网球女孩还挺可爱的
Tennis girl's kind of cute.
天呐  克里夫
Geez, Cliff.
这太诡异了
This is way too creepy.
天啊
Oh, God.
我认识这些小孩
I know those kids.
但是他们都死了
But they're all dead.
小心  克里夫
Watch it, Cliff.
你一定要这样吗
Did you have to do that?
不好意思  我没看见他
I'm sorry. I didn't see him.
无所谓的  明迪
Well, it doesn't matter, Mindy.
他们已经死了
They're already dead.
准确来说  是活死人
Well, undead, to be precise.
复活了
Reanimated.
该死的闯入者
Fucking trespasser.
去死吧
Kiss your ass goodbye.
该死  他们都是从哪冒出来的
Shit, where are they all coming from?
看起来没什么动静
It seems pretty quiet.
不过三号房间的门是开着的  我去看看
But door number three is open, so I'm gonna check it out.
我们一起去
Let's both check it out.
我也一起去
Well, I'm coming, too.
太惨了
That's bad.
丧尸未逝
斯特吉尔·辛普森
Sturgill Simpson.
天啊
Oh, my God.
你为什么要这么做
Why did you do that?
他们不是僵尸
They're not zombies.
他们不过是死人而已
They're just dead people.
目前他们只是死了的潮人而已
Well, yeah, for now, they're still just dead hipsters,
还没转变成僵尸
but they haven't turned yet.
需要一点时间
It can take a while.
他说得对  明迪
He's right, Mindy.
现在他们才是...
Now they're just...
死透了的克利夫兰潮人
dead hipsters from Cleveland.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我受不了
I can't.
天啊
My God.
看看你们
Well, look at all of you.
饥渴贪婪
So very ravenous,
但是早就该死了
yet well past your expiration date.
天呐  好好瞧瞧这俩
Oh, man. Get a load of these two.
咖啡
Coffee.
丧尸未逝
天啊
Oh, God.
又是这首歌
Not that again.
斯特吉尔·辛普森
Sturgill Simpson.
♪ 丧尸正如你我 ♪
♪ Oh, the dead don't die ♪
好歌
Great song.
♪ 每日半死不活 ♪
♪ Any more than you or I ♪
♪ 他们只是活在 ♪
♪ They're just ghosts inside a dream ♪
♪ 虚妄的白日梦中 ♪
♪ Of a life that we don't own ♪
♪ 他们就在你我身边 ♪
♪ They walk around us all the time... ♪
要死啊  听不下去了
Goddamn it. I can't take any more.
有些冲动啊  克里夫
That was irrational, Cliff.
操  你觉得汉克和鲍比·威金斯还在里面吗
Fuck. Do you think Hank and Bobby Wiggins are still in there?
我们要去救他们出来吗
Should we try to get 'em out?
克里夫  我们吸引了一些注意力
Cliff, we're drawing some attention.
天啊  克里夫
Oh, God, Cliff.
快带我们离开
Please get us out of here.
求你了  克里夫
Please, Cliff. Please.
应该能撑住
That should hold.
该死的僵尸  鲍比
Goddamn zombies, Bobby.
我认识他们
I know those guys.
他们是我最好的顾客
They were two of my best customers.
对  古德兄弟
Yeah, yeah, the Good brothers.
崔维斯·古德和达拉斯·古德
Travis and Dallas Good.
以前死于一场车祸
They died in a car crash some time back.
该死
Oh, shit.
我想起他们了
Yeah, now I remember those guys.
古德兄弟
The Good brothers.
他们很会弹吉他
They were really good guitar pickers.
没错  就好像他们是
That's right. It's-it's like they came out of the birth canal
抱着吉他出生的
with guitars in their hands.
我觉得你救了我的命
I think you saved my life, man.
别客气  汉克
No worries, Hank.
该死
Shit.
-怎么了  -该死的后门
- What? - The fucking back door.
通向储藏室的后门
The back door to the storage room.
-什么  -这边
- What? - Here.
天啊  鲍比
Jesus, Bobby.
该死
Shit.
太多了  汉克
There's way too many, Hank.
这就是场噩梦  鲍比
This here is a nightmare, Bobby.
我们死定了  伙计
We're goners, man.
操
Fuck.
快点  给我
Come on. Give me that!
真是想不到
Well, I'll be a monkey's ass.
报应终于来了
It's finally payback time.
你们这些该死的难民  我要把你们都抓起来
You goddamn refugees! I'll get all of you!
你们要为此付出代价
You're gonna pay for this!
滚出我的地盘
Get off my property!
这鸡确实好吃
This is good chicken.
该死的
Damn it!
你不下去看看吗
You want to get out and check?
还是算了吧
I'd-I'd rather not.
真是太美妙了  不是吗
Well, that's perfect, isn't it?
身处该死的墓园
Right in the middle of the fucking cemetery.
一点也不美妙
No, it isn't perfect.
你为什么要开车碾它们
Why did you run over them?
它们不是普通的行人
They are not ordinary pedestrians.
绝对不会有好结局
This is definitely gonna end badly.
闭嘴  罗尼
Shut up, Ronnie.
不  你闭嘴
No, you shut up.
闭嘴  罗尼
Shut up, Ronnie!
别吵了好吗
Please stop fighting.
拜托
Please.
明迪
Mindy.
Mindy...
是我奶奶
It's my grandmother.
天啊  奶奶
Oh, God, Granny.
-明迪  明迪  -不
- Mindy, Mindy. - No.
明迪  振作点
Mindy, get it together.
它生前是你奶奶
It was your grandmother.
我受不了了
I can't take this anymore.
我撑不下去了
I can't do it!
我受够了这场噩梦
I'm done with this nightmare.
奶奶  我来了
Granny, I'm coming.
-我来了  -明迪
- I'm coming. - Mindy?
不  明迪  不要
No, Mindy! No, don't!
不
Oh, no!
我操
Holy fuck.
上帝保佑我们
God help us.
森特维尔
Centerville.
美国
USA.
一个好地方
A real nice place.
真是台有趣的小机器
What an amusing little machine.
这位挺好玩的
Here's a curious one.
你好啊
Hello there.
时尚
Fashion.
我可以明确告诉你  这条格子裙不适合你
I can assure you that is not your tartan.
不过脖子挺好看的
Nice neck, though.
来吧  我知道躲在哪里最安全
Come on. I know a safe place we can hide.
该死
Oh, shit.
那是丹尼·珀金斯吗  这边的
Is that Danny Perkins? Over here.
看起来是他没错
Sure looks like him.
罗尼  抱歉我发脾气了
I'm sorry, Ronnie, if I've lost it.
没关系  克里夫
It's okay, Cliff.
不过我得说
But I got to say,
自从开始发生这些怪事
you have been acting a lot different
你就变得很不一样
since all this weird shit started happening.
你想说什么  克里夫
What-what are you saying, Cliff?
我想说你看起来异常地沉着
I'm saying that you seem so oddly controlled.
见鬼了
I mean, shit.
我只是在用自己的方式应对
Well, I'm just, you know, dealing with it in my own way.
不过我一直在跟你说  不会有好结局
But I've been telling you this is all gonna end badly.
该死的  罗尼
Goddamn it, Ronnie.
我能问你一个问题吗
May I ask you a question?
当然  尽管问吧
Sure. Ask away.
你确实一直在说
You have been saying
不会有好结局  从一开始就说了
that this is all gonna end badly, from the very beginning,
说了一遍又一遍
over and over.
你他妈怎么能这么肯定
So, what made you so fucking sure of that?
你怎么能事先知道一切
How did you know everything in advance?
你真的想知道吗
Do you really want to know?
对
Yes!
我想知道  我真的想知道
I want to know. I really want to know!
好吧  我知道是因为我读了剧本
Okay. I know because I've read the script.
你
You...
读了剧本
read the script.
完整的剧本
The whole script?
从头到尾
All of it?
是啊  吉姆给了我完整的剧本
Yeah. Jim gave me the whole script.
本片导演吉姆·贾木许
他只给我看了我们演的部分
He only gave me our scenes.
我没看过完整的剧本
I never saw a complete script.
我为那家伙付出了那么多
After all... I've done for that guy.
而且很多事你都不知道
And it's a lot that you don't even know about.
真是个混蛋
What a dick.
真奇怪
That's weird.
他们都走了
They're all leaving.
好  来了
Right. Here we go.
你也看到那个了吗
Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
好像看到了
I think I am.
那个也在剧本里吗
Was that in the script?
没有
No.
起码我读过的没有
Not the one I read.
真是出乎意料
Well, that was unexpected.
我就知道她不同寻常
I knew there was something unusual about her.
嗯
Yeah.
罗尼  结局是怎样的呢
So, Ronnie, how does it end, then?
这个嘛
Well...
我们必须全力以赴
We got to give it our best shot.
"全力以赴"
"Our best shot."
好吧
Okay. Yeah.
然后不会有好结局  对吧
But then it ends badly, right?
对
Yeah.
不会有好结局
Yeah, it does.
那好吧
Okay, then.
我们上
Let's do it.
克里夫和小罗尼
Cliff and little Ronnie.
勇士
Warriors.
被死者包围
Among the dead.
僵尸
Zombies.
苟延残喘的实利主义者
Remnants of the materialist people.
你休想  你休想
Oh, no, you don't. No, you don't.
也许他们本来就是行尸走肉
I guess they've been zombies all along.
鬼魂
Ghosts.
鲍比
Bobby.
该死
Shit.
"无数凡人的无名苦难"
"Nameless miseries of the numberless mortals."
弗兰克
Frank.
这是你自找的
You got this coming.
再见  弗兰克
Goodbye, Frank.
罪有应得
You reap what you sow.
下一个是谁
All right, who's next?
真恶心
Yuck.
好了
All righty.
把头抬起来
Hold your head up.
奶奶
Granny.
明迪会希望你向爷爷问好
Mindy would want you to say hi to Grandpa.
汉克
Hank.
很抱歉  兄弟
I'm so sorry, brother.
我下不了手
I just can't do it.
照顾好自己
You take care of yourself.
丹尼
Danny.
我刚刚见到汉克了
I just saw Hank.
尘归尘
Ashes to ashes.
土归土
Dust to dust.
罗尼
Ronnie.
明迪
Mindy!
克里夫
Cliff.
罗尼
Ronnie.
不
No!
天啊  罗尼
Jesus, Ronnie.
死人今天就是不想死
The dead just don't want to die today.
死而复生  惊慌失措
Reanimated and all jacked up,
像那些蚂蚁一样
just like those ants.
世界末日
The end of the world.
我猜那些亡灵都失去了灵魂
I guess all them ghost people plumb lost their goddamn souls.
肯定是把灵魂卖了
Must have traded 'em away
换了黄金之类的
or sold 'em for gold or whatnot.
新卡车  厨房设备
New trucks, kitchen appliances,
新裤子  任天堂游戏机
new trousers, Nintendo Game Boys,
诸如此类的垃圾
shit like that.
总是欲求不满
Just hungry for more stuff.
他们倒下了
Down they go.
克里夫和罗尼的悲惨结局
The sad end of Cliff and Ronnie.
真是个操蛋的世界
What a fucked-up world.
♪ 丧尸正如你我 ♪
♪ Oh, the dead don't die ♪
The Dead Don't Die - Sturgill Simpson
♪ 每日半死不活 ♪
♪ Any more than you or I ♪
♪ 他们只是活在 ♪
♪ They're just ghosts inside a dream ♪
♪ 虚妄的白日梦中 ♪
♪ Of a life that we don't own ♪
♪ 他们就在你我身边 ♪
♪ They walk around us all the time ♪
♪ 永远心不在焉 ♪
♪ Never paying any mind ♪
♪ 不管我们活得荒唐 ♪
♪ To the silly lives we lead ♪
♪ 还是死得凄凉 ♪
♪ Or the reaping we've all sown ♪
♪ 每个转角都有一杯咖啡 ♪
♪ There's a cup of coffee waiting on every corner ♪
♪ 有一天我们醒来 ♪
♪ Someday we're gonna wake up ♪
♪ 会发现转角不见了 ♪
♪ And find the corners gone ♪
♪ 但是丧尸仍独自 ♪
♪ But the dead will still be walking round ♪
♪ 在这旧世间漫步 ♪
♪ In this old world alone ♪
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on ♪
♪ 将有老友漫步 ♪
♪ There'll be old friends walking round ♪
♪ 在似曾相识小镇 ♪
♪ In a somewhat familiar town ♪
♪ 当你不再盯着手机 ♪
♪ That you saw once ♪
♪ 抬头曾目睹 ♪
♪ When you looked up from the phone ♪
♪ 没人费心打招呼 ♪
♪ Nobody bothers saying hi ♪
♪ 你也大可直接上路 ♪
♪ And you can save all your goodbyes ♪
♪ 别再试图假装 ♪
♪ Stop trying to pretend ♪
♪ 你我并不孤独 ♪
♪ That we're all not at home ♪
♪ 清晨街头空无一物 ♪
♪ And the streets look so empty in the morning ♪
♪ 无人再需 ♪
♪ There'll be no one out at night ♪
♪ 夜灯引路 ♪
♪ For the lights to shine down on ♪
♪ 但是丧尸仍独自 ♪
♪ But the dead will still be walking round ♪
♪ 在这旧世间漫步 ♪
♪ In this old world alone ♪
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on ♪
♪ 亲人逝去 ♪
♪ Hearts break ♪
♪ 命赴黄泉 ♪
♪ When loved ones journey on ♪
♪ 如此一想 ♪
♪ At the thought ♪
♪ 心碎难捱 ♪
♪ That they're now forever gone ♪
♪ 所以我们告诉自己 ♪
♪ So we tell ourselves they're all still ♪
♪ 他们一直都在我们身边 ♪
♪ Around us all the time ♪
♪ 已逝却未被遗忘 ♪
♪ Gone but not forgotten ♪
♪ 只余回忆心中藏 ♪
♪ Just memories left behind ♪
♪ 但是丧尸仍独自 ♪
♪ But the dead will still be walking round ♪
♪ 在这旧世间漫步 ♪
♪ In this old world alone ♪
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on ♪
♪ 在生命走到尽头后 ♪
♪ Oh, well after life is over ♪
♪ 死后故事拉开序幕 ♪
♪ The afterlife goes on. ♪